<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Accelerated `ggplot2` on Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing</title>
    <link>/tutorials/r-extra/accelerated-ggplot2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Accelerated `ggplot2` on Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tutorials/r-extra/accelerated-ggplot2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Basic Plotting in `ggplot2`</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-extra/accelerated-ggplot2/ggplot_summer2018_part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-extra/accelerated-ggplot2/ggplot_summer2018_part1/</guid>
      <description>Make ’em Graph Welcome! This tutorial will cover some basics of scatter plots, time series data, and some alternatives to bar graphs (for categorical predictors and continuous outcomes). It will also go over a few handy things along the way, such as making graphs with multiple panels, and aesthetic mapping for clearer plots.
Note: All examples here will be with simulated data, so that as we are making our plots we can be aware of the TRUE data generating processes and assess how well our graphs represent these.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Advanced `ggplot2` Plotting</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-extra/accelerated-ggplot2/ggplot_summer2018_part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-extra/accelerated-ggplot2/ggplot_summer2018_part2/</guid>
      <description>God grant me the serenity to accept the uncertainty I cannot control; courage to control the uncertainty that I cannot accept; and wisdom to know the difference. -Andrew Gelman
All models are wrong, but some are useful - George Box
1) Overview Welcome! This tutorial will cover some aspects of plotting modeled data within the context of multilevel (or ‘mixed-effects’) regression models. Specifically, we’ll be using the lme4, brms, and rstanarm packages to model and ggplot to display the model predictions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
