<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>core on Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing</title>
    <link>/tags/core/</link>
    <description>Recent content in core on Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/core/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Programming in R</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming, Part 0</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart0/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the CU Psychology Scientific Computing workshop!
Programming is telling a computer to do some action to some input info to get output info that you want. When it comes to working with data in R, programming is how we tell R to load data, process it, plot it, fit models to it, and so on (everything!).
In this first section of our tutorial, we will learn about this info that goes in and out, as well as the actions that transform info into what we want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming, Part 1</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart1/</guid>
      <description>Welcome (back) to the CU Psychology Scientific Computing Workshop! As a reminder, the documents for the introduction to programming cover the following:
Programming, Part 0: Finding your way around RStudio Programming, Part 1: Variables, data types, vectors (this document!) Programming, Part 2: Coding strategy, relational &amp;amp; logical operators Links to Files and Video Recording The files for all tutorials can be downloaded from the Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing GitHub page using these instructions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming, Part 2</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart2/</guid>
      <description>Welcome (back) to the CU Psychology Scientific Computing workshop! As a reminder, the documents for the introduction to programming cover the following:
Programming, Part 0: Finding your way around RStudio Programming, Part 1: Variables, data types, vectors Programming, Part 2: Coding strategy, relational &amp;amp; logical operators (this document!) Now that you know (some of) what kinds of things R can manipulate, we will get into actually manipulating things!
Links to Files and Video Recording The files for all tutorials can be downloaded from the Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing GitHub page using these instructions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Cleaning</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/2-datacleaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/2-datacleaning/</guid>
      <description>Goals of This Lesson Students will learn:
How to open various data types in R How to check for missing or problematic data and address issues. How to filter, rearrange and shape data in preparation for analysis. Links to Files and Video Recording The files for all tutorials can be downloaded from the Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing GitHub page using these instructions. This particular file is located here: /content/tutorials/r-core/2-datacleaning/index.rmd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Manipulation</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/3-datamanipulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/3-datamanipulation/</guid>
      <description>Goals of This Lesson Learn how to group and categorize data in R Learn how to generate descriptive statistics in R Links to Files and Video Recording The files for all tutorials can be downloaded from the Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing GitHub page using these instructions. This particular file is located here: /content/tutorials/r-core/3-datamanipulation/index.rmd.
For a video recording of this tutorial from the Fall 2020 workshop, please visit the Workshop Recording: Session 2 page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting with `ggplot2`</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/4-plotting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/4-plotting/</guid>
      <description>What Is This Tutorial? What’s ggplot2? ggplot2 is a package in R that allows for highly customizable and pretty plots! Here, were going to learn a few basics of making plots using ggplot2 that will hopefully get you well on your way to making informative and beautiful data visualizations!
Links to Files and Video Recording The files for all tutorials can be downloaded from the Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing GitHub page using these instructions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/5-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/5-modeling/</guid>
      <description>Goals of This Lesson Learn about functions and syntax for models in R Practice examples of different model types Understand how to obtain model results in R
Learn how to visualize the results of the models Links to Files and Video Recording The files for all tutorials can be downloaded from the Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing GitHub page using these instructions. This particular file is located here: /content/tutorials/r-core/5-modeling/index.rmd.
For a video recording of this tutorial from the Fall 2020 workshop, please visit the Workshop Recording: Session 2 page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R to Python Translation</title>
      <link>/tutorials/python/1-r2python-translation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/python/1-r2python-translation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing Between R and Python</title>
      <link>/tutorials/python/1-r2python-translation/0-python-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/python/1-r2python-translation/0-python-r/</guid>
      <description>Links to Files and Video Recording The files for all tutorials can be downloaded from the Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing GitHub page using these instructions. This particular file is located here: /content/tutorials/python/1-r2python-translation/0-python-r.ipynb.
For a video recording of this tutorial from the Fall 2020 workshop, please visit the Workshop Recording: Session 3 page.
A few quick points: Among scientific computing languages the best language for you is the one that you find best fits your projects We really encourage the use of either R and Python for research computing for several reasons R and Python are open source!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Jupyter Notebooks</title>
      <link>/tutorials/python/1-r2python-translation/1-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/python/1-r2python-translation/1-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Goals: Students will feel comfortable navigating the jupyter notebook layout Students will be able to access their computer&amp;rsquo;s file structure through jupyter notebook Links to Files and Video Recording The files for all tutorials can be downloaded from the Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing GitHub page using these instructions. This particular file is located here: /content/tutorials/python/1-r2python-translation/1-getting-started.ipynb.
For a video recording of this tutorial from the Fall 2020 workshop, please visit the Workshop Recording: Session 3 page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Programming in Python</title>
      <link>/tutorials/python/1-r2python-translation/2-intro-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/python/1-r2python-translation/2-intro-programming/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer! This intro programming tutorial in Python is NOT nearly as comprehensive as the intro programming tutorial in R. If you have never programmed in any language before, this tutorial may skip key pieces of information. Instead, the goal of this tutorial is to provide some key pieces of &amp;rsquo;translation&amp;rsquo; information for people with some programming experience who would like to use Python. Goals of this Lesson Students will: Understand and be comfortable working with the basic data types in Python Be able to use arithmetic, relational operators, and lists in Python For those coming from R, be aware of differences across languages, especially in indexing Links to Files and Video Recording The files for all tutorials can be downloaded from the Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing GitHub page using these instructions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control Flow in Python</title>
      <link>/tutorials/python/1-r2python-translation/3-control-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/python/1-r2python-translation/3-control-flow/</guid>
      <description>Goals of this lesson Students will learn: How to use if/else and for loops in python How to indent code correctly in python Links to Files The files for all tutorials can be downloaded from the Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing GitHub page using these instructions. This particular file is located here: /content/tutorials/python/1-r2python-translation/3-control-flow.ipynb.
Indenting in python Python, unlike R, is strict about indentation! Indentations in python often have bearing on the order in which they are executed, and switching indentation can change how code runs (or break it) Coming from R, indentation might seem annoying at first, but eventually this can help with code readability Ultimately, python is trying to help us stay organized If statements If statements in python are the equivalent of the following English: &amp;ldquo;If condition X is met, then do action Y&amp;rdquo; If statements in python consist of the following syntax if (condition X): actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Cleaning in Python</title>
      <link>/tutorials/python/2-datacleaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/python/2-datacleaning/</guid>
      <description>Goals of this Lesson Students will learn: How to open various data types in Python How to check for missing or problematic data and address issues How to filter, rearrange and shape data in preparation for analysis Links to Files and Video Recording The files for all tutorials can be downloaded from the Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing GitHub page using these instructions. This particular file is located here: /content/tutorials/python/2-datacleaning/index.ipynb.
For a video recording of this tutorial from the Fall 2020 workshop, please visit the Workshop Recording: Session 3 page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Manipulation in Python</title>
      <link>/tutorials/python/3-datamanipulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/python/3-datamanipulation/</guid>
      <description>Goals of this Lesson Students will learn: How to group and categorize data in Python How to generative descriptive statistics in Python Links to Files and Video Recording The files for all tutorials can be downloaded from the Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing GitHub page using these instructions. This particular file is located here: /content/tutorials/python/3-datamanipulation/index.ipynb.
For a video recording of this tutorial from the Fall 2020 workshop, please visit the Workshop Recording: Session 3 page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting in Python Using `matplotlib` and `seaborn`</title>
      <link>/tutorials/python/4-plotting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/python/4-plotting/</guid>
      <description>Goals of this Lesson Students will learn: How to generate beautiful statistical visualizations in Python using the seaborn package Links to Files and Video Recording The files for all tutorials can be downloaded from the Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing GitHub page using these instructions. This particular file is located here: /content/tutorials/python/4-plotting/index.ipynb.
For a video recording of this tutorial from the Fall 2020 workshop, please visit the Workshop Recording: Session 3 page.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
