<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>core on Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing</title>
    <link>/tags/core/</link>
    <description>Recent content in core on Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/core/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Descriptives</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/3-descriptives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/3-descriptives/</guid>
      <description>Goals for this tutorial: Learn how to group and categorize data in R Learn how to generate descriptive statistics in R   0. Open dataset and load package This dataset examines the relationship between multitasking and working memory. Link here to original paper by Uncapher et al. 2016.
# use read.csv function to open data into R df &amp;lt;- read_csv(here(&amp;quot;content&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;tutorials&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;r-core&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;3-descriptives&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;uncapher_2016_repeated_measures_dataset.csv&amp;quot;)) # we will continue using tidyverse tools # so we have library()-ed tidyverse at the very top of this document  1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting your data ready for analysis</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/2-datacleaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/2-datacleaning/</guid>
      <description>Goals of this lesson Students will learn:
How to open various data types in R How to check for missing or problematic data and address issues. How to filter, rearrange and shape data in preparation for analysis.   Install Packages tidyverse is one package with many tools. We will introduce you to this package in this lesson, and continue using tidyverse in the next module.
 Getting your Data into R Entering data directly In some cases, you may want to enter data directly into R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/5-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/5-models/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the lesson on modeling in R!
Goals:
Learn about functions and syntax for models in R Practice examples of different model types Understand how to obtain model results in R
 Learn how to visualize the results of the models  Let’s get some data.
We will use the same data we are already familiar with from the Descriptives lesson. We will compute a group for high and low ADHD, so we can use that in our models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting Tutorial Using ggplot2!</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/4-plotting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/4-plotting/</guid>
      <description>0: What is this tutorial? What’s ggplot2? ggplot2 is a package in R that allows for highly customizable and pretty plots! Here, were going to learn a few basics of making plots using ggplot that will hopefully get you well on your way to making informative and beautiful data visualizations!
 1: First Load Tidyverse, which includes ggplot2! We’ve already done this in the special first chunk up top, so it should run automatically before you run any chunk of code lower in the document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming, pt 0</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart0/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the CU Psychology Scientific Computing workshop!
Programming is telling a computer to do some action to some input info to get output info that you want. When it comes to working with data in R, programming is how we tell R to load data, process it, plot it, fit models to it, and so on (everything!).
In this first section of our tutorial, we will learn about this info that goes in and out, as well as the actions that transform info into what we want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming, pt 1</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart1/</guid>
      <description>Welcome (back) to the CU Psychology Scientific Computing Workshop! As a reminder, the documents for the introduction to programming cover the following:
Finding your way around RStudio Variables, data types, vectors this document! Coding strategy, relational &amp;amp; logical operators  Variables  a variable is how we store information in a way that the computer can operate on it has a value: the info itself and a name: the cue by which we call upon the info to the computer  If you think about how variables like x and y are used in algebra, calculus, etc, that can be a useful way to conceptualize them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming, pt 2</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart2/</guid>
      <description>Welcome (back) to the CU Psychology Scientific Computing workshop! As a reminder, the documents for the introduction to programming cover the following:
Finding your way around RStudio Variables, data types, vectors Coding strategy, relational &amp;amp; logical operators this document!  Now that you know (some of) what kinds of things R can manipulate, we will get into actually manipulating things!
Pseudocode This is so important to do before you write a single line of code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>