<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Descriptives</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/3-descriptives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/3-descriptives/</guid>
      <description>Return home Goals for this tutorial: 0. Open dataset and load package 1. Familiarize yourself with the data 2. Selecting relevant variables 3. Basic Descriptives  Summarizing data  4. Grouping data 5. Extra: Working with a long dataset  How many unique subjects are in the data Make sure you know how many trials there were per subj. Combine summary statistics with the full data frame  6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting your data ready for analysis</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/2-datacleaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/2-datacleaning/</guid>
      <description>Goals of this lesson Install Packages Getting your Data into R  Entering data directly Reading data into R  Inspecting your data  How is your data frame structured? Brief intro to tidyverse Rename a variable Check for missing data Check for correct values Filtering data  Getting ready for analysis  Recoding variables Calculating new variables Combining data from multiple sources Shaping data  Saving your work Data Challenge!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/license/</guid>
      <description>License Instructional Material All CU Psych Computing instructional material is made available under the Creative Commons Attribution license. The following is a human-readable summary of (and not a substitute for) the full legal text of the CC BY 4.0 license.
You are free:
 to Share—copy and redistribute the material in any medium or format to Adapt—remix, transform, and build upon the material  for any purpose, even commercially.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetings</title>
      <link>/meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/meetings/</guid>
      <description>  Meetings Come and learn with us at one of our meetings! Topics span various early-intermediate to advanced strategies for asking psychological research questions using scientific computing tools.
Upcoming To be announced.
 Past Under construction! Documentation of past meetings will be added soon.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/5-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/5-models/</guid>
      <description>Basics for modeling in R  Functions:  Basic models  Syntax:  Basic model formula To add multiple factors Interactions  Output of models  Linear models Anova  Visualizing models Advanced models    Welcome to the lesson on modeling in R! Goals: 1. Learn about functions and syntax for models in R 2. Practice examples of different model types 3. Understand how to obtain model results in R</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting Tutorial Using ggplot2!</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/4-plotting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/4-plotting/</guid>
      <description>Return home 0: What is this tutorial? What’s ggplot2? 1: First Load Tidyverse, which includes ggplot2! 2: Load in Sample Data (NHANES) 3: Scatter Plot &amp;amp; Basic ggplot Syntax  3a: Histograms with ggplot  4: Dot Plot Organized by Grouping Factor  4a: Visualizing Distributions with Violin Plots  5: Summary Plots 6: Fitting Lines To The Data 7: Titles, Axis Labels 7: Facetting 8: Color 9: Themes 10: Saving To Files 11: Heatmaps 12: Basic Time Series Plot 13: Final Points   Return home Click here to return to the main CU psychology R tutorials page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming, pt 0</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart0/</guid>
      <description>Working with RStudio  Installing R &amp;amp; RStudio Getting oriented to the RStudio window  R project files Console window Editor window Environment/history window Files/pkgs/help window  Installing and loading packages  Working directories, file paths, etc  The working directory File paths  Absolute file paths Relative file paths Special file path keywords  Reading data into R  Generating a file path using here() Reading the data into R Loading the file as an R object     Welcome to the CU Psychology Scientific Computing workshop!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming, pt 1</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart1/</guid>
      <description>Variables Data types  Numeric data  Arithmetic operators  Logical data Character data Dataframe columns have data types too  Data structures  Data frames  Working with dataframe columns Summarizing dataframe columns Indexing into dataframes  Vectors  Indexing into vectors   Data types pt 2  Factor data Non-data data    Welcome (back) to the CU Psychology Scientific Computing Workshop! As a reminder, the documents for the introduction to programming cover the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming, pt 2</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart2/</guid>
      <description>Pseudocode Relational operators  Filtering data Operating on filtered data  Logical operators Conditional operators Functions  Anatomy of a function Writing your own function  Getting assistance  On your own  The help docs The internet  Asking someone else  How to ask     Welcome (back) to the CU Psychology Scientific Computing workshop! As a reminder, the documents for the introduction to programming cover the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/</guid>
      <description>Resources Columbia-Specific Resources  Columbia Psychology scientific computing users Slack group)   Full, Freestanding General-Use R Tutorials Mainly base R tutorials  Cookbook for R: Basics of data cleaning, analysis and graphing   Tidyverse tutorials  Hadley Wickham’s R for Data Science online textbook Michael C. Frank’s psychology-specific tidyverse tutorial, adapted from R for Data Science   Syllabi for courses taught in R You can work along with these; course materials should be linked in the syllabi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy walkthrough, part 1</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-extra/tidyverse-guide/tidyguide-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-extra/tidyverse-guide/tidyguide-1/</guid>
      <description>Goals for this vignette  Please keep in mind!  Quick cheat-list of key functions from various pkgs Brief intro to the pipe Initializing fake data Loading data Visually inspecting data Subsetting data  Subsetting by column Subsetting by row  Logical subsetting Subsetting rows by position Getting only unique/un-duplicated rows Subsetting random rows  Subsetting by row and column simultaneously  Manipulating data  Creating/modifying columns  Nice helpers  Calculating summary statistics  Special versions of summarize()  Grouping  Mutating grouped data Summarizing grouped data When to ungroup your df  Creating new rows  Repeating existing rows Completing combinations of grouping variables   Reshaping data  From wide to long  Pivot-longering multiple distinct variables at once  From long to wide  Pivot-widering multiple distinct variables at once   Coming up in part 2   Goals for this vignette  Demonstrate (what I think are) key first-level features of the tidyverse Illustrate psychology use cases for tidyverse functions Hopefully convince you to join the cult of tidy  We shall do this by walking through various use cases you might encounter with your data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy walkthrough, part 2</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-extra/tidyverse-guide/tidyguide-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-extra/tidyverse-guide/tidyguide-2/</guid>
      <description>Goals for this vignette Quick cheat-list of key functions from various pkgs Initializing fake data Joining dfs Nested dfs  A brief (re)view of lists Lists as df columns  A df with a list-column still behaves like a df, mostly df-ception: df list-columns that contain other dfs   Vectorizing to the high heavens  Vectorizing: it’s like a for loop, but not Tidy vectorizing  Intro to map() Special versions of map() Using map() on list-columns inside a df  When not to vectorize  Working with model objects en masse  Fitting a whole lotta models Extracting model coefficients  Plotting data   Goals for this vignette Hello (again)!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who We Are</title>
      <link>/who/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/who/</guid>
      <description>Who We Are 2020 - 2021 Graduate Methods Support Advisors Emily Nakkawita  Research interests: how goal pursuit processes differ based on individuals’ unique motivational orientations Method specialties: surveys, web-based response latency tasks Tool/language specialties: R, generating manuscripts with Papaja, Javascript/HTML customization in Qualtrics, M-Turk, Prolific Favorite NYC neighborhood: Park Slope Office hours: To be announced   Hannah Tarder-Stoll  Research interests: how memory is flexibly used to predict future events at different timescales Method specialties: cognitive tasks (in-person and web-based), neuroimaging, virtual reality Tool/language specialties: R, Python, Unity, Inquisit Favorite NYC neighborhood: Astoria Office hours: To be announced     Contributors to Scientific Computing Workshop The lesson materials for the introductory workshop are the evolving product of several contributors, past and present, from the Columbia University psychology department.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop</title>
      <link>/workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/workshop/</guid>
      <description>Fall 2020 Workshop Instructors: Paul A. Bloom, Emily Nakkawita, Jonathan Nicholas, Matt Siegelman, Hannah Tarder-Stoll, Monica Thieu
 General Information This workshop develops and teaches the scientific computing skills needed to conduct psychological research. Its target audience is researchers who have little to no prior computational experience, and its lessons are psychology-specific, building on learners’ existing knowledge to enable them to quickly apply skills learned to their own research.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>