<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming in R on Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing</title>
    <link>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming in R on Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming, Part 0</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart0/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the CU Psychology Scientific Computing workshop!
Programming is telling a computer to do some action to some input info to get output info that you want. When it comes to working with data in R, programming is how we tell R to load data, process it, plot it, fit models to it, and so on (everything!).
In this first section of our tutorial, we will learn about this info that goes in and out, as well as the actions that transform info into what we want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming, Part 1</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart1/</guid>
      <description>Welcome (back) to the CU Psychology Scientific Computing Workshop! As a reminder, the documents for the introduction to programming cover the following:
 Programming, Part 0: Finding your way around RStudio Programming, Part 1: Variables, data types, vectors (this document!) Programming, Part 2: Coding strategy, relational &amp;amp; logical operators  Links to Files The files for all tutorials can be downloaded from the Columbia Psychology Scientific Computing GitHub page. This particular file is located here: /content/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming, Part 2</title>
      <link>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/r-core/1-programming/lessonpart2/</guid>
      <description>Welcome (back) to the CU Psychology Scientific Computing workshop! As a reminder, the documents for the introduction to programming cover the following:
 Programming, Part 0: Finding your way around RStudio Programming, Part 1: Variables, data types, vectors Programming, Part 2: Coding strategy, relational &amp;amp; logical operators (this document!)  Now that you know (some of) what kinds of things R can manipulate, we will get into actually manipulating things!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>